Ivan Chew Instructional Designer

in LinkedIn ★ Portfolio Website ✔ Vimeo

• Medium

OVERVIEW

Grounded by adaptability and a collaborative spirit, my global experience in teaching and entrepreneurship has been enriching. In a constant cycle of learning and growth, I've sharpened my ability to deliver immersive learning experiences. As a dedicated lifelong learner, I understand and effectively meet adult learners' needs. Embracing new challenges, I leverage my experiences while relishing the rewarding journey of continual learning and creativity.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PE Head of Department. Outdoor Education. Digital Media, IST

• Crafting interactive & gamified activities on ManageBac, Seqta, and Moodle LMS

• Cultivating creativity & inclusivity in the IB digital media with awards and challenges

Business, Entrepreneurship and Digital Media Teacher, CISE

• Collaborative group challenges to ignite creativity, fuel motivation, & promote growth

Developed wide array of differetiated classes for diverse interests & learning needs

Business and PE Instructor, Maple Leaf International Schools 2

• Empowering non-native English speakers through dynamic and tailored lessons

• Hands-on, real world, project based and individualized tasks for aspiring entrepreneurs

Proprietor / Marketing Director, Avenue Bar

Crafting seamless user experiences, captivating visuals, & maintainable websites

Forging a distinctive brand and training staff for bar program and company ethos

August 2017 - June 2022

Dar es Salaam, Tanzania

July 2015 -

September 2017

Cairo, Egypt

August 2011 - June 2014

Dalian, China

May 2010 - August 2013

Kelowna, Canada

FORMAL EDUCATION

Cybersecurity, Skills for Hire Atlantic / BlueDrop ISM ☑

Currently enrolled in 20 week program. AWS / ISACA / ISC -CC certification.

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp Diploma, Lighthouse Labs

Intensive & immersive 12-week project-focused remote learning bootcamp

Bachelor of Education, *University of Alberta*

Secondary/Middle School. English and Social Studies specialization

July 2023 - December 2023 Liverpool, Canada

February 2023 - May 2023

Trenton, Maine, USA

2002 - 2007

Edmonton, Canada

HARD SKILLS

General IT Skills (Moodle, ManageBac, SEQTA, Articulate360, Zoom, Trello, Google/Microsoft Suite, OpenAi)

Design skills: (Adobe Illustrator/Photoshop, Figma, Canva, Luminar, Final Cut Pro, Podcasts & screencasts, Nikon SLRs)

Coding Languages, Libraries & Frameworks: (Javascript, NodeJS, React, Ruby on Rails, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, PostgreSQL, Storybook, Ajax, Express, EJS, Material UI, ANT UI, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, SASS, bcrypt)

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Surf eLearning Course, Created on Articulate 360 and Rise 360 ☑

June 2023

· Conducted thorough research and curated resources for course development

• Interactive features to enhance the content, boosting UX accessibility & engagement.

EAIT, Ai powered recipe app with practical & polished UX/UI interface. □

April 2023

• Drove the ideation, pitch, and wireframe creation for a responsive React.JS / MUI app

· Created an inclusive collaboration ensuring progress and input from all team members

Extended Studies Program Consultant, International School of Tanganyika

September 2019 -

Orchestrated training & education of all community stakeholders for Tanzania wide trips

· Creation of website and its content to inform and help organize all groups for each trip

June 2022

February 2019

Expedition Coordinator and Adventure Leader, Mt Kilimanjaro

• Balanced teaching with management of travel, documentation, & equipment logistics

• Recruitment of 4 teachers, doctor, training and equipping 19 students for 7 day climb

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Adventurous Surfer (Exploring the maritime coast with 'Bessie' our campervan in search of empty and perfect waves), Videographer / Photographer (who loves to capture raw landscapes, natural wildlife and unique personalities), **Ukulele Devotee** (Late-blooming serenader who enjoys learning and covering surf and travel inspired melodies), Writing / Blogging (Capturing intriguing narratives, transcribing tales of bygone times, distant travels & inspirations.)